welcome back to another audacity
欢迎回到另一个大胆的地方
tutorial in this video I want to quickly
在这段视频中 我想快速了解
show you how to add markers to a file
演示如何向文件添加标记
you're working with an audacity or you
你要么胆大妄为 要么就是
can also do this one live recording over
也可以做这一次现场录制
on the YouTube channel Brody Hansen
在YouTube频道Brody Hansen上
asked about this how to add markers
问到这一点如何添加标记
during an interview so they know how to
在面试中 这样他们就知道如何
quickly jump to certain questions in
快速跳转到中的某些问题
that interview so I'll show you how to
所以我会告诉你怎么做
do that it's actually just a ctrl M on
这样做 实际上只需按下Ctrl M即可
your keyboard so if we play back this
你的键盘 所以如果我们回放这个
file we can hit ctrl M on the keyboard
文件 我们可以在键盘上按Ctrl M键
and every time we do that holding down
每次我们这样做的时候 我们都会忍住
ctrl and pressing the M key will add a
按住Ctrl键并按M键将添加一个
marker down here on our audio file we
在我们的音频文件上做标记
can then pause and we can zoom in here
可以暂停 然后我们可以放大这里
or we can just click on Maya please do
或者我们可以只点击Maya 请这样做
min so we can zoom and look at these
最小 这样我们就可以放大并查看这些
markers and we know that during these
标记 我们知道在这些期间
points we can call this you know soft
分数 我们可以称之为软性的
part of the song you're right and then
这首歌的一部分你是对的然后
like building or whatever kind of notes
比如建筑或其他任何类型的音符
we want to have we can come and add them
我们想要 我们可以来加
in here I'm gonna show you - if we just
在这里 我要向你展示-如果我们
go ahead and then we can just clear all
去吧 然后我们就可以清场了
this out we can delete these and we can
这一次我们可以删除这些 我们可以
record a new track this is my so
录制一首新曲目这是我的苏珊
question number one and we've add the
第一个问题 我们添加了
marker there how do you feel about this
你对此有何感想？
a little bit of blah okay question
有点废话 好吧 问个问题
number two add marker you know what's
第二 添加记号笔 你知道什么是
your favorite food so this is the
你最喜欢的食物所以这是
interview then we just come down here we
采访然后我们就到这里来我们
hit ctrl M on the keyboard to create
按键盘上的Ctrl M以创建
these and then we just title it question
这些 然后我们就把它命名为问题
number one and then go to the next one
第一个 然后去下一个
title it question number two so fairly
标题是第二个问题 很公平
simple just need to know the shortcut
简单只需知道捷径即可
key ctrl M and then you can zoom out
按Ctrl M键 然后您就可以缩小
really far and be able to jump to your
真的很远 并且能够跳到您的
questions very quickly not sure if we
问得很快 我不确定我们是否
can I think if we click on these we
我能不能认为如果我们点击这些
could we can move them around to once
我们能不能把它们移到一次
they're already placed by left clicking
它们已经通过左键点击放置了
and dragging
和拖拽
oh and cool we can highlight a selection
哦 酷 我们可以突出显示一个选择
as well I didn't realize that so if we
我也没有意识到 所以如果我们
go to the end part of it we can move it
走到最后一部分我们可以移动它
but we can also say this question is
但我们也可以说这个问题
this duration so everything spanning
这段时间
here is question number two so we could
下面是第二个问题 我们可以
even overlap certain markers can overlap
甚至重叠某些标记可以重叠
each other anyway a really useful tool
无论如何 一个非常有用的工具
when using audacity hopefully that helps
当使用audacity时 希望这有助于
and go ahead and leave your questions or
留下你的问题
comments below if you have any and look
下面的评论 如果你有任何 看看
forward to catching you in the next
期待着在下一个
you
你